impactana.com 2015-11-01

# Impactana GmbH | Privacy Policy

## **Functionality and Privacy** **  Policy**

**www.impactana.com**

Impactana is a specialized search engine with additional features. The services are offered by Impactana GmbH, FN 431538 s, Leonard Bernstein Straße 10 / 7th floor, 1220 Vienna, Austria. Impactana GmbH is also responsible for processing your personal data. 

You can find more information about us in the imprint of our homepage. 

Changes in responsibility will be published on our website, especially in the imprint, and in the current version of this document. They will be announced to our registered customers via email.

**Data**

We collect information to provide search services to our customers.

Search engines are essential for the simplification of search and evaluation of the relevance of information on the World Wide Web. Our search engine also assesses the scope, dissemination, effect and resonance of content and people in the Web via the evaluation of „Buzz“ and „Impact“ metrics.

We offer different search parameters to enhance and structure search results.

For search results on persons we only use data that subjects published themselves, or that were made public by third parties, for example in the context of journalistic articles, blogs, posts, comments, or other digital publications.

We offer wo/man the possibility to opt out of the search on their person and from the evaluation of their personal "impact" and "buzz", by sending us an e-Mail.

When using our services data are processed at different  **levels** :

1)  **Data that users provide as part of our contractual relationship:**

Data are necessary to create an account and for the administration of the contract, i.a. for the billing of our services. During the registration on [www.impactana.com](http://www.impactana.com/) or related websites owned by Impactana GmbH or partners of Impactana GmbH we ask the user to enter personal data such as name, profession, email and physical addresses, telephone number(s), credit card number and optionally their social network accounts like Twitter, Facebook.

The records produced thereby will not be disclosed to third parties, except for our billing and accounting purposes, including data processing by our service partners, on which we impose strict commitment to privacy.

The data will be processed only as required to fulfill the contract and will be erased upon termination of the contract, except for contractual or legal obligations to the contrary.

2)  **Data we receive due to the use of our services:**

We collect device-specific information such as the model of hardware, the version of the operating system, device identifiers and information about the mobile network including your phone number. Impactana may connect your device identifiers with your Impactana account.

Log Data: If you use our services or access content submitted by Impactana, we capture and store data in server logs . These protocols include the following:

Details on the way you have used our services, for example, your searches or usage of the application.

IP address: Data of events such as visits, the date and time of your requests and the Referral URL.

Cookies that can identify your browser or your account. You can choose whether to accept cookies or reject them, by changing the settings in your browser. 

**Cookies and similar**   **technologies**

We use different technologies in order to acquire and store data, if you use Impactana‘s services. These include cookies or similar technologies to identify your browser or device. Furthermore we use these technologies to record and store data, if you interact with services of our partners, such as advertising services or Impactana features on other websites.

If you are logged into your Impactana Account data we capture might be linked with your account. We will always treat the data linked with your Impactana Account as personal data.

**Usage of our websites and tools**

Our websites and tools allow users to learn more about our company, download content and provide us with contact details and other demographic information. This information is saved on the servers of our software partner HubSpot. We shall be entitled to use this information to establish contact with the visitors of our website(s), and to determine which of our company products and services are relevant to our visitors. Any and all information collected shall be subject to the provisions of this Privacy Statement. We undertake to use the information collected exclusively for marketing purposes and/or lead generation. HubSpot is a software company based in the U.S., with a branch office in Ireland. Contact details: HubSpot, 2nd Floor 30 North Wall Quay, Dublin 1, Ireland, Phone: +353 1 5187500. HubSpot is subject to the TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal and the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework

**Clear Gifs**

We use a so-called Clear Gifs software that helps us improve our subscription service by informing us which content is effective. Clear Gifs are small graphics with a unique identifier (similar to cookies) that help analyze the user behavior of website visitors. In contrast to cookies that are stored on a user’s device, Clear Gifs are invisibly embedded on websites and in e-mails and are usually about the size of a pixel. We use Clear Gifs in our HTML-based emails to see which e-mails were opened. We can thereby evaluate the effectiveness of communication actions and marketing activities. We combine this information with personal data. You can unsubscribe from such e-mails.

You may unsubscribe from our e-mail communications at any time by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link at the end of the e-mail.

**Google Analytics**

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies, text files that are stored on your device and that allow for analyzing your website usage and behavior. The information about your website usage generated via the cookie is usually transmitted to and stored by Google’s servers located in the United States. On behalf of the website owner, Google will evaluate the information in order to analyze your website behavior, to compile reports about the website activities and to render further services to the website owner related to the website and Internet usage. The IP address transmitted from your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be associated with any other data held by Google. You may reject the storage of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings of your browser; please not, however, that in this case you may not be able to use the full functionality of our websites. Furthermore, you can prevent the data generated by the cookie and relating to your use of the website (including your IP-address) from being transferred to and/or processed by Google, by downloading and installing the following browser plugin: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en

**Use of the collected information:**

We use the data collected during the use of our services to provide the services, for maintenance, for the protection and improvement and development of more accurate services, in order to serve the needs of users, and to protect our company and our community of users.

We use this information to offer personalized content and services and to provide you with more relevant search results. If you contact us actively, we may record your communication. We will also send you information about changes, improvements, and contractual adjustments via e-mail or traditional mail.

Data collected through cookies and other technologies help us to improve the usability and quality of our services. We do not connect data collected with Cookies and similar technologies with sensitive data, such as data on race, religion, sexual orientation or health. We do not create any databases, summarizing people according to their race, religion, philosophy, sexual orientation or health characteristics.

**Opting Out**

We generally offer wo/man the possibility to block personal search on her own person, without stating any cause at all, by sending an e-mail message to [hello@impactana.com](mailto:hello@impactana.com). For protection against abuse by third parties, it is required that you provide us with a copy of an official photo ID or certified electronic signature and provide a physical address and telephone number.

**Incorrect, illegally published, outdated, copyright infringing, defamatory or discrediting information**

Besides the general opting out we give you the possibility to individually oppose content referenced by our results, whether due to inaccuracy, illegality of publication, lack of timeliness, potential credit damage or breach of copyright as well as other legitimate interests. We will block such results within the framework of the technical possibilities and subject to an internal review. Please keep in mind that a permanent or complete removal from the WWW can only be achieved directly at the source of the publication. We are neither able nor obliged to completely delete the contents from the WWW, blockage by us can take place only within our search results.

**Information about the data stored on your person**

You can, request information on the data we have stored on you. For protection against abuse requests must be identified (see „Opting Out“). We will then send you a file on a suitable storage medium.

**Update and remove personal data**

We strive to keep all data correct. We offer you the opportunity to update the data collected by ourselves and to remove incorrect information, unless we have to keep it due to legal requirements, or to administer our contract with you. We reserve the right to decline requests for information and updating, if inquiries are repeated inappropriately, or require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of third parties, etc.

**Third-party content**

We assume no liability for third party content, and do not endorse the opinions and statements expressed therein. We are responsible for the sorting and processing of our own results.

**Social Media features**

Our websites use Social Media features like “Facebook Share Buttons” and/or widgets like “Share this”-Buttons or other widgets. Such features can register your IP-address and record the page(s) you visited. They can also use cookies. Social Media features and widgets are provided to our websites by third parties. This Privacy Statement does not apply to such services. The terms of usage of the providers of such features are governed by their own privacy policies.

**External websites**

Our websites contain links to other websites. We shall not be obliged to verify foreign websites, nor shall be held liable for any of the content or actions on foreign websites. Our links to foreign websites do not allow any conclusions about whether or not we agree with their content or whether or not we support their website owners. This Privacy Statement does not apply to websites we link to. 

**Public forums and blogs**

We offer publicly accessible forums and blogs that allow you to publish messages. Please keep in mind that any and all information you publish on publicly accessible forums and blogs on our websites may be registered and used by third parties. If you wish, we will edit or delete any information you published on our websites. We reserve the right to delete posts that contain offensive content or that are otherwise deemed inappropriate by us.  

**"Buzz" and "Impact"**

With our evaluation functionalities "Buzz" and "Impact" we estimate the reach and the public feedback to people and digitally published content and contributions. We use algorithms programmed upon a variety of criteria, but we also include the feedback of other users and our personal experience.

We might add personal data, in particular name, e-mail addresses, phone numbers etc. to the search results, but credit card numbers or social security numbers are never added.

Our ratings "Buzz" and "Impact" are our personal individual opinions and conclusions drawn from the processed content and information, statistics and other data published by third parties, including Likes, Cheers, User Comments, Follower Statistics etc. Our estimates and classifications do not claim absolute validity or correctness. For the sake of objectivity our ratings are not negotiable, and never to be bought or manipulated. We reserve corrections due to technical errors.

We provide the possibility of Opting Out (See above) from personal evaluation.

**Impactana Toolbar**

Together with the online app, our team developed the Impactana toolbar.

The Impactana content marketing toolbar (Alpha Version) is free and easy to use. It provides you with a very powerful set of metrics right in your browser.

You can identify powerful content, new trends and popular authors. For every new page, our toolbar will show you a wide set of Buzz and Impact metrics¹.

**By installing and using the Impactana Toolbar you agree to the following terms and privacy policy:**

To make the Impactana Toolbar features work, the extension collects information about the websites you visit and the date of your visit. Once you enable the Impactana Toolbar, our servers receive the URL²  you currently visit, so we can send you back the Buzz and Impact metrics.

We don’t do this to creep where you surf to and we will not keep  personalized records on your surfing habits longer than necessary. Honestly, we  don’t care where you surf to, but theoretically we would be able to track your  surf behavior with that information.  If you want to avoid us indexing some URLs you surf to, you can easily disable  the toolbar on a domain by domain basis by clicking “Disable toolbar on this  domain”. Then our servers won’t receive any data about your visit to the domains  you disabled the toolbar for. On those domains we won‘t show you the toolbar. This  means you can fine-tune which URLs you want to send to us.

²URL: Uniform Resource Locator: a protocol for specifying addresses on the Internet. An address that identifies a particular file on the Internet, usually consisting of the protocol, as http, followed by the domain name.

**Data security**

We protect our services and the data stored in accordance with the state of technology and sensible business practices with reasonable efforts against accidental or willful access, and destruction by third parties.

**Liability**

We are liable for damages only if caused intentionally or by gross negligence by Impactana, our employees or agents.

We constantly review and update the content published on our websites. However, we do not assume any liability or guarantee for the current relevance, correctness and/or completeness of the information provided.

The liability for consequential damages is excluded.

Jurisdiction is Vienna, Austrian law applies.

**Contact for data protection:**

Our services are rendered evaluating the right to privacy and the public interests of access to information and free speech, the interests of our users and the technical and conceptual foundations of the World Wide Web, offering the possibility to opt out of personal searches, rectification or blocking of obsolete, illegally published, damaging or incorrect search results and information on stored data upon request, in accordance with the European Data Protection Directive and the Austrian Data Protection Act.

We will examine criticism and suggestions, and will adjust our data protection standards according to experience and changing requirements.

For questions regarding the collection, processing or use of your personal data please contact us at:

**Impactana GmbH**  
Leonard-Bernstein-Straße 10 / Floor 7  
Saturn Tower  
1220 Vienna, Austria, Europe  
Austria

**Phone/Fax/e-mail:  
** Phone AT: +43 1 890 45 00  
Fax AT:  +43 1 953 50 19  
Phone US :  +1 866 347-3660  
Phone UK:  +44 800 011 9736Phone  
NL: +31 85 888 1541Phone  
IE: +353 76 680 1480Phone  
CA: +1 877 736-7787  
Email: [hello@impactana.com](mailto:hello@impactana.com)

**Company Registration Data (“Impressum”)**  
Company Reg Nr. : FN 431538s  
Tax Reg. Nr. : 562/3843  
VAT-ID: ATU69449019  
Gewerbereg.Reg. : 27584989, MBA22  
Jurisdiction/Gerichtsstand : Wien  
Applicable Law : Austria
